Guide to the Operations and Maintenance Dept. Records, 1919 - 1957
Duke University. University Archives
- S.W. Myatt Files, 1927-1957
  - Sarah P. Duke Gardens - Drainage Area, 1934-1937 (Box 7, Folder 253)
    Includes 4 site plans.
  - Sewer Line serving Duke and VA Hospital, 1945-1950 (Box 7, Folder 254)
  - Sewer Lines - Chapel Hill Road, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 255)
  - Shands Residence (Dr. A.R.) on Anderson Street, [undated] (Box 7, Folder 256)
    Includes 7 architectural drawings and building plans.
  - Social Sciences Building (formerly Physics) - Blueprints, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 257)
  - Social Sciences Building (formerly Physics) - Proposed Addition, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 258)
  - Southgate Hall - Proposed Addition, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 259)
  - Statue - James B. Duke, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 260)
  - Storage Warehouse Addition, 1943-1948 (Box 7, Folder 261)
  - Swimming Pool (West Campus), 1936 (Box 7, Folder 262)
  - Trent Drive Hall, 1950-1953 (Box 7, Folder 263)
  - Trent Drive Hall - Blueprints and Specifications, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 264-265)
  - Trinity College Bell and Cornerstones, 1928, 1938-1943 (Box 7, Folder 266)
  - Union Building
    - Alterations
      - Architect: Office of Horace Trumbauer, 1953-1955 (Box 7, Folder 267)
      - Blueprints, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 268)
      - Contractors, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 269)
      - Financial Statements, 1953-1955 (Box 7, Folder 270)
      - Specifications, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 271)
    - Proposed Addition, [undated] (Box 7, Folder 272)
    - Proposed Additions, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 273)
      Includes 6 building plans.
    - Suggestions for Portrait Locations, [undated] (Box 7, Folder 274)
      Includes 2 architectural drawings.
  - University House, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 275)
  - Use of Aeronautics Building for NROTC Armory (Proposed), 1947 (Box 7, Folder 276)
  - Veterans Enrolled, 1947-1948 [RESTRICTED - Student Records] (Box 7, Folder 277)
  - Wannamaker Residence Hall - Financial Statements, 1956-1957 (Box 8, Folder 278)
  - Warehouse Building for Drama, 1947-1948 (Box 8, Folder 279)
  - West Campus Heating Plant Extension, 1950-1953 (Box 8, Folder 280)
  - West Campus Women's Toilet Facilities, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 281)
  - YMCA Cabin (Proposed), 1938 (Box 8, Folder 282)
  - York Chapel - Blueprints, 1930 (Box 8, Folder 283)
  - Keys (Box 11)
    - Key to Gym (Box 11)
    - Key to Lobby to Office - East Duke (Box 11)
    - Key to Back East Door - Craven (Box 11)
    - Key to Box of Lantern Slides (Box 11)
    - Key to Office in Old Post Office (Box 11)
    - Key to Architect's Room (Box 11)
    - Old Dope Shop Key (Box 11)
    - Key to Towel Cabinet (Library) (Box 11)
    - Key to Toilet Paper Cabinet (Box 11)
    - Key to Filing Cabinets (Box 11)
    - Key to Key Cabinet - Old Campus (Box 11)
    - Key to Mr. Duke's Desk (Box 11)
    - Adjusting Key to Thermostat (Box 11)
    - Key to Gates in Quadrangle (Box 11)
    - Key to Front Door to West Duke (Box 11)
    - Key to Old Tom Rigsbee House on Rigsbee Road (Williamson) (Box 11)
    - Key to Potato Room on the Rigsbee Place (Box 11)
    - Key labeled "To Dr. Brown by Murray Jones. From: W.D. Mooney" (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous unmarked keys (Box 11)
- Duke Construction Company Records, 1927-1957
  The Duke Construction Company was formed in 1927 on the advisement of the Building Committee of the Duke Endowment. In a letter to Duke president R.L. Flowers, N.A. Cocke, Assistant Secretary of the Duke Endowment, wrote:
  "It is hardly practicable to conduct the operations in the name of the trustees of The Duke Endowment for the reason that The Duke Endowment has no separate entity apart from the trustees, it not being a corporation. On the other hand while the title to the property is in Duke University the Will and Trust Indenture contemplate that the trustees shall erect the buildings for Duke University and turn same over when completed. With the idea, therefore, of establishing some medium for the purpose of carrying on this construction, it has occured to us that it would be wise to form a corporation, known as the "Duke Construction Company" for the sole purpose of constructing these buildings, with a nominal capital stock so that it will clearly appear that this corporation is merely an agency for carrying out this work."
  The Duke Construction Company series consists mainly of financial and corporate records, such as articles of incorporation, tax reports, and a large invoice register. Actual construction plans can be found in the Frank C. Brown Files series and the S.W. Myatt Files series.
  The Duke Construction Company was active in the 1930s and into the 1940s, but it then became dormant and was officially dissolved in 1957.
  - Chart of Accounts, 1927, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 284)
  - Chart of Accounts for Private Patients Building, Indoor Stadium, and Few Quadrangle, 1938-1939 (Box 8, Folder 285)
  - Construction Plans, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 286)
  - Corporate Tax Reports, 1927-1942 (Box 8, Folder 287)
  - Cost Analysis Information for Duke Endowment, 1931-1940 (Box 8, Folder 288)
  - Estimates of Costs - "New" Duke University, 1928 (Box 8, Folder 289)
  - Incorporation, 1927-1931, 1954-1957 (Box 8, Folder 290)
  - Invoice Register (includes index), 1938-1940 (Box 8, Folder 291)
  - Minutes
    - Board of Directors, 1927-1942 (Box 8, Folder 292)
    - Duke University Building Committee, 1945-1948 (Box 8, Folder 293)
    - Hospital Building Committee, 1944-1948 (Box 8, Folder 294)
  - Nurses Home Agreement between Duke University and Dr. and Mrs. Frederic Hanes, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 295)
  - Re-valuation of West Campus Buildings, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 296)
    Includes a detailed list of costs per building.
  - Statement of Construction Ledger, 1931 (Box 8, Folder 297)
  - Statement of Estimated Costs, Expenditures, and Obligations, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 298)
- Desk Diaries, 1931-1949
  The Desk Diaries series contains 19 volumes of diaries that detail daily events held at Duke. The Operations and Maintenance department served as the central booking agency for campus events, and these diaries record events, places, and times over a nearly twenty-year period.
  - 1931 (Box 9, Folder 299)
  - 1932 (Box 9, Folder 300)
  - 1933 (Box 9, Folder 301)
  - 1934 (Box 9, Folder 302)
  - 1935 (Box 9, Folder 303)
  - 1936 (Box 9, Folder 304)
  - 1937 (Box 9, Folder 305)
  - 1938 (Box 9, Folder 306)
  - 1939 (Box 9, Folder 307)
  - 1940 (Box 9, Folder 308)
  - 1941 (Box 9, Folder 309)
  - 1942 (Box 9, Folder 310)
  - 1943 (Box 10, Folder 311)
  - 1944 (Box 10, Folder 312)
  - 1945 (Box 10, Folder 313)
  - 1946 (Box 10, Folder 314)
  - 1947 (Box 10, Folder 315)
  - 1948 (Box 10, Folder 316)
  - 1949 (Box 10, Folder 317)
    This diary is located in Box 8.
Related Material
Brown (Frank C.) Papers, 1899-1943
Duke University Archives
Business Division Records
Duke University Archives
Building Reference Collection
Duke University Archives
Horace Trumbauer Architectural Drawings Collection
Duke University Archives